Finding Aid to the Dee Mosbacher papers and Woman Vision records SSC.MS.00740
Sophia Smith Collection
- Woman Vision records, 1950-2014; 1984-2013; 2; 61.28 linear feet (97 boxes)
  - Training Rules
    - Research: NCLR/WV/Helen, 2001-2009 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: Artlcles to consider, 2006-2007 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: B-Roll needed all lists, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: Center Court requests, special collections library, approximately 2006-2009 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: List of library videos, etc./Courtney Wick article, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: Microfilm articles, 1991-2006 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Research on PSU/Rene Portland: Penn State Lady Lions game notes, 1996-1997 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Research: Penn State Library media permissions and conditions, plus communications, 2001 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Research: PSU, 2007-2009 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Research: PSU DVDs/Center Court, 2002-2007 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Research: PSU/non-discrimination policy, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Research: PSU shoot b-roll compilation, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Research: PSU vs. Illinois game - Sue Rankin instructional video, 2007-2008 (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Research: Rene Portland "Coach of the Year", approximately 1991-2004 (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Research: Rene Portland - mommy coach, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Research: Rene Portalnd - positive/laudatory articles about her, 2004-2007 (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Research: Rene - Protests, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - Research: Rene Portland "Renaissance Award", 2005 (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - Research: Program binder, National Gay and Lesbian Althletics conference, 2003; 2 folders (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
    - Research: Sports, 1999 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Research: Sports Illustrated and annotated list of featured photographs, 2004-2006; 2 folders (Box 78, Folder 4-5)
    - Research: Lydia Szyjka to Dee Mosbacher, approximately 1991-2009 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Research: Texas Monthly, 2005 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Research: WBCA (Women's Basketball Coaches Association) code of ethics, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Research: WBCA conference, 2009 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Research: Women in Intercollegiate Sport: A Longitudinal, National Study, Thirty One Year Update, 2008 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - The Last Challenge: About page, 2012 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: Add to email now, 2013 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Advisory board resource list/affirmatives, 2012 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Agents, 2011 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - The Last Challenge: AP images/Library of Congress, 2012 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - The Last Challenge: Tart house info, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Articles, 2012; 2 folders (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
    - The Last Challenge: Aspiration tech, undated, approximately 2012 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: Aspiration tech, campaign strategies, goals, schedule, video topics, branding, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - The Last Challenge: Ben and Jerry's complete, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - The Last Challenge: Ben and Jerry's complete, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - The Last Challenge: Binders, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - The Last Challenge: Bios (Jen Missing), approximately 2011-2012 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - The Last Challenge: Bitly, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - The Last Challenge: Bleacher creatures, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - The Last Challenge: Blog information, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: Blog pages with blogs, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Boston shoot, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Budgets, 2012-2013; 2 folders (Box 79, Folder 14-15)
    - The Last Challenge: Call sheet, San Francisco, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Call sheets, 2011-2012 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - The Last Challenge: Campaign page, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - The Last Challenge: Charles N. Matthewson Foundation, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - The Last Challenge: Chicago City Council official agenda plus, 2013 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - The Last Challenge: Chicago speakers list, letters of support, contact info, 2013 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - The Last Challenge: Cinematographers, approximately 2009-2013 (Box 79, Folder 22)
    - The Last Challenge: Cinematographers LA, Main HD on Lacie Office, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 23)
    - The Last Challenge: College and WR-Marilyn Guttell, approximately 2009-2012 (Box 79, Folder 24)
    - The Last Challenge: Columbia, 2009-2011 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - The Last Challenge: Comcast Sports Net, 2011-2012 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - The Last Challenge: Comerica Charitable Foundation, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: Commissioners, 2011-2012; 2 folders (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    - The Last Challenge: Contact info for Commissioners Office, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - The Last Challenge: Contact us page, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - The Last Challenge: Cyd Zeigler, Jim Bruziski, NY Times article, 2013 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - The Last Challenge: Cyd's article, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - The Last Challenge: David Kopay, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - The Last Challenge: Donation page/body page, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: Dream Host, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Dropbox, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Duplicate notes/Facebook, Twitter, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - The Last Challenge: Elefint Web Design, Gopika Prabu, Matthew Sharpnick, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - The Last Challenge: Elvis Murks, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Elvis Murks changes, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - The Last Challenge: Email Now/Woman vision Inc, wacrycha, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - The Last Challenge: Equipment/Dee's, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - The Last Challenge: Eric Anderson, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - The Last Challenge: ESPN contacts, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - The Last Challenge: Ewan Duarte/Intern, approximately 2009-2012 (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - The Last Challenge: Fawn's questions, Nike LGBT Sports Summit, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - The Last Challenge: Fawn's talking points, Chicago, approximately 2013 (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - The Last Challenge: Ford Foundation, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - The Last Challenge: Free Conference Call, 2013 (Box 80, Folder 26)
    - The Last Challenge: From Grant folder, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - The Last Challenge: Galen Dodd, Grady Schroeder, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 28)
    - The Last Challenge: Germeshausen Foundation, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 29)
    - The Last Challenge: Gill Foundation, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 80, Folder 30)
    - The Last Challenge: Google info, 2011-2012 (Box 80, Folder 31)
    - The Last Challenge: Google webmaster links, approximately 2012 (Box 80, Folder 32)
    - The Last Challenge: Gwen Knapp, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 33)
    - The Last Challenge: Gwen Knapp/Hardaway, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 34)
    - The Last Challenge: Home page, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 35)
    - The Last Challenge: Howard Bagman-Questions, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 80, Folder 36)
    - The Last Challenge: Images purchased/licensed, AP images, RF images, 2012 (Box 80, Folder 37)
    - The Last Challenge: Intern, 2013 (Box 80, Folder 38)
    - The Last Challenge: ITVS - completes work commissioned funding, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - The Last Challenge: ITVS/open call, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - The Last Challenge: KALW-Lisa Denenmark, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: Kevin Lynch, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - The Last Challenge: Kids, 2011-2012 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - The Last Challenge: Kobe Bryant, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - The Last Challenge: Larry Baer interview, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - The Last Challenge: Letter of interest, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - The Last Challenge: Letters of interest/lists, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - The Last Challenge: LGBT Sports Coalition Nike, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - The Last Challenge: LGBT Sports summit at Nike attendees (missing TLC) goals, agenda, shoot budget, 2012 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: LOGOS TLC, approximately 2012 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Lookout/fundraiser raised 900 plus, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Mac Arthur drafts, 2011; 2 folders (Box 81, Folder 14-15)
    - The Last Challenge: Mailing list sign-up, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Media campaign, approximately 2011-2012 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - The Last Challenge: Michael Irwin, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - The Last Challenge: Michael Pritchard, approximately 2011-2013 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - The Last Challenge: Miscellaneous info, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - The Last Challenge: Nike Sport Summit people, 2012 (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - The Last Challenge: Noah fined/homo slur, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - The Last Challenge: Notes, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - The Last Challenge: Oakland resolution, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - The Last Challenge: Official Chicago resolution, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - The Last Challenge: Old notes, 2012 (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - The Last Challenge: Olympic chief resigns over gay marriage, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - The Last Challenge: On the team: Equal opportunity for transgender student athletes, 2010 (Box 81, Folder 28)
    - The Last Challenge: Open Society Institute, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 29)
    - The Last Challenge: Opportunities, 2012-2013 (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - The Last Challenge: Options for closing down site, undated, approximately 2012 (Box 81, Folder 31)
    - The Last Challenge: Organizational chart, approximately 2011-2013 (Box 81, Folder 32)
    - The Last Challenge: Outlook, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 33)
    - The Last Challenge: Owners, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 34)
    - The Last Challenge: Phone rap, approximately 2013 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - The Last Challenge: Portlana/Nike Summit, 2013 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - The Last Challenge: Poster/Dana Kelley, approximately 2012-2013 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: Press, 2008 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - The Last Challenge: Press center for website, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - The Last Challenge: Press conference, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - The Last Challenge: Press contacts, 2013 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - The Last Challenge: Press release, 2012-2013 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - The Last Challenge: Release forms, approximately 2009-2012; 2 folders (Box 82, Folder 9-10)
    - The Last Challenge: Rene Richards, approximately 2009-2012 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: Resolution coalition, 2012-2013 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Resources page/body page, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Resume, approximately 2009-2012 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - The Last Challenge: Rick Welts, NBA executive, comes out, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - The Last Challenge: Robeson Fund, Out Fund, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Rosenthal Family Foundation, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - The Last Challenge: Safety nets for LGBT athletes, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - The Last Challenge: Sample web pages for The Last Closet, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - The Last Challenge: Samuel Rubin Foundation, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - The Last Challenge: San Francisco press conference resolution, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - The Last Challenge: San Francisco resolution with city seal, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 22)
    - The Last Challenge: Script - early trailer, Cyd Zeigler in Los Angeles, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 23)
    - The Last Challenge: Script for trailer, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 24)
    - The Last Challenge: Sean Avery, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 25)
    - The Last Challenge: Sponsors, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 26)
    - The Last Challenge: Stand Up Foundation budget/grant proposal, 2009-2013 (Box 82, Folder 27)
    - The Last Challenge: StandUp Magazine, 2012-2013 (Box 82, Folder 28)
    - The Last Challenge: submit a video/ body page, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 29)
    - The Last Challenge: Sundance, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 30)
    - The Last Challenge: Telephone spiel for interns, approximately 2009-2013 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - The Last Challenge: The Last Closet campaign, 2013 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - The Last Challenge: TLC general notes/pages, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: TLC press/body page, 2008-2012 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - The Last Challenge: TLC scripts, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - The Last Challenge: TLC treatment for film documentary, approximately 2009-2012 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - The Last Challenge: To do, 2012-2013 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - The Last Challenge: Travel info/boarding pass, miscellaneous info, 2013 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - The Last Challenge: Tumblr, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - The Last Challenge: Twitter page.body page, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - The Last Challenge: Two straight athletes, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - The Last Challenge: Video page, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - The Last Challenge: Wallace Global Fund, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - The Last Challenge: Web notes/beta test, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - The Last Challenge: Web pages/Elefint, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - The Last Challenge: Website designers/proposals, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - The Last Challenge: Websites on resource page, 2012 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - The Last Challenge: Writers Guild of America West treatment registration, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - The Last Challenge: Yip Harburg, 2011 (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Audiovisual materials and film documentation, 1981-2009; 7 boxes (Box 84-90)
    - Computer files related Training Rules production
      - Digital images and documentation for Training Rules film production, 2003-2009; 47 Gigabytes (89 ISO disc images from 89 data CDs; and 1 E01 disk image from 1 floppy disk)
        This digital content is not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access.
        Other Finding Aids
        For a complete list of disc titles, see the attached log file. Digital file lists for individual discs are available upon request.
      - Training Rules - Edit Backup Drive #1, 2007-2009; 475 Gigabytes (10,133 digital files copied from 1 hard drive)
        Video production files for Training Rules
      - Training Rules - Edit Drive #2, 2007-2009; 458.5 Gigabytes (3,712 files)
      - Training Rules - Edit Backup #3, 2007-2009; 428.73 Gigabytes (4581 digital files copied from 1 hard drive)
      - Training Rules. Editor's Backup; several rough cuts, 2007-2009; 93.58 Gigabytes (8,291 digital files copied from 1 hard drive)
        (from labels on drive) "Training Rules" - Motion Graphics; Editor's Backup; several rough cuts; Includes trans. & articles; Jennifer Durso's work. QT Files only."
  - Woman Vision
    This sub-series includes audiovisual materials from other films like Boys in Winter: The Toughest Season, Pink Houses; news pieces; sports games between PSU and other schools; transcriptions; photographs; notes; treatments; media backups; video logs; grant proposals; articles and press releases; interviews.
    - Administrative: Working business plan, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Administrative: Distribution, 1998-2002 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Films: AGC, SFTH, OFAC synopsis, credits, showings, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Films: Film Festivals, 2000-2001 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Films: Important papers, 1994-2001 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Marketing, 1995 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Post and Audio, 1997 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Projects: Coming Out, Coming Home, approximately 1998 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Films: History of Women's Music notes, 1997-2002; 5 folders (Box 91, Folder 9-13)
    - Films: History of Women's Music transcripts, approximately 1997-2002; 4 folders (Box 91, Folder 14-17)
    - South Africa Project: Miscellaneous, 2005 (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - South Africa Project: Tape log, 2005; 2 folders (Box 92, Folder 1-2)
    - The Last Challenge: To Fawn, 2012 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - The Last Challenge: Transcripts, 1999-2005; 14 folders (Box 92, Folder 4-17)
    - Research: Miscellaneous Articles, 1992-1994 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Research: Gay bashing, anti-gay legislation, 1991-1993 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Research: Gay issues, 1993 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Research: Radical right, 1994 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Woman Vision promotional, outreach, and interview audiovisual materials, 1993-2003 (Box 94)
    - Women's Empowerment fundraising and project audiovisual materials, 1996-2001; 2 boxes (Box 94, Box 95)
    - Montclair Show audiovisual materials, 1999 (Box 96)
    - South Africa Project audiovisual materials, 1962-2005; 3.5 boxes (Box 96, Box 97, Box 99, Box 100)
      - Computer files for South Africa project, 2004-2005; 1.5 Gigabytes (15 ISO disc images from 15 data CDs)
    - The Last Challenge, 2003-2011; 2 boxes (Box 98, Box 99)
    - Woman Vision - Digital masters - all footage, 2015; 98.95 Gigabytes (8 digital files copied from 1 hard drive)
      D. Mosbacher and Woman Vision Films: Master (.mov) files of 8 films:
      De Colores Closets are Health Hazards Out for a Change Radical Harmonies All God's Children Training Rules Straight From the Heart Lesbian Physicians on Practice, Patients and Power
  - Hard drives, 2002-2009; 3 boxes (7 external hard drives) (Box 101, Box 102, Box 103)
    As a preservation measure, the hard drives in these boxes are restricted. The contents of the hard drives has been copied to networked storage and are described within the appropriate series in the container list. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to digital copies.